Okay. What is up, De Anza students? I'm Chris
Koranda and I'm excited for our fall 2026
Introduction to Personal Finance class. You
may have found your way to this class because
you have an interest in personal finance and you
want to learn a little bit more about the topic.
And I think that's great. You may have found your
way to this class because there's somebody that
you trust in your life who told you the topic is
important and that you should try to learn more.
And I think that's fantastic. And finally, you may
have found your way to this class because none of
the classes that you actually wanted to take were
available when you went to register. And that is
totally okay as well. Maybe don't make a point
of telling me this when you see me in person,
but regardless of how you found yourself in this
class, I'm happy that you are here and I'm excited
to go on this journey with you. Just a little
bit more about me. I studied business in college
and then I've spent the last 25 years working
in finance. I'm teaching this class because I
truly love the topic and because I believe that
a knowledge of finance and in particular personal
finance has the ability to be transformative in
your life. My goal for you this quarter is that
you leave this class with both the knowledge and
the confidence to make all of the most important
financial decisions that you will face in your
life. So, if you found your way to this video,
you're off to a great start in terms of preparing
for the class. No need to overwhelm you with an
entire quarter's worth of details right now.
We can do a lot more when we see each other
in person. I think above all else, what I want you
to take away right now is that I'm here to support
you on your journey and I'm here to make sure that
you accomplish all of your goals for yourself this
quarter. Before we see each other, if you have any
questions...questions like, Chris, did you nail
this video in one take? No, I did not. Chris, how
many times did you mispronounce personal finance?
Definitely more than one. Or any other questions
that might be relevant before we start the class.
Feel free to reach out. There is a link to my
email on this website. I'd be happy to hear
from you. If not, I hope you enjoy the rest of
your summer and I'm excited to see you soon.